<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upgrade on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upgrade on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 3.5 Minor Versions</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading Postgres Operator 3.5 Minor Versions This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade Postgres Operator 3.5 minor releases.
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! Prerequisites. You will need the following items to complete the upgrade:
 The latest 3.5.X code for the Postgres Operator available The latest 3.5.X PGO client binary Finally, these instructions assume you are executing from $COROOT in a terminal window and that you are using the same user from your previous installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 3.5 to 4.3.0</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35to4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35to4/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading a Cluster from Version 3.5.x to PGO 4.3.0 This section will outline the procedure to upgrade a given cluster created using Postgres Operator 3.5.x to PGO version 4.3.0. This version of the Postgres Operator has several fundamental changes to the existing PGCluster structure and deployment model. Most notably, all PGClusters use the new Crunchy Postgres HA container in place of the previous Crunchy Postgres containers. The use of this new container is a breaking change from previous versions of the Operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 4.X to 4.3.0 (Ansible)</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade4xto42_ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade4xto42_ansible/</guid>
      <description>Postgres Operator Ansible Upgrade Procedure from 4.X to 4.3.0 This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade to version 4.3.0 of the Crunchy Postgres Operator using the Ansible installation method. This version of the Postgres Operator has several fundamental changes to the existing PGCluster structure and deployment model. Most notably, all PGClusters use the new Crunchy Postgres HA container in place of the previous Crunchy Postgres containers. The use of this new container is a breaking change from previous versions of the Operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 4.X to 4.3.0 (Bash)</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade4xto42_bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade4xto42_bash/</guid>
      <description>Postgres Operator Bash Upgrade Procedure from 4.X to 4.3.0 This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade to version 4.3.0 of the Crunchy Postgres Operator using the Bash installation method. This version of the Postgres Operator has several fundamental changes to the existing PGCluster structure and deployment model. Most notably, all PGClusters use the new Crunchy Postgres HA container in place of the previous Crunchy Postgres containers. The use of this new container is a breaking change from previous versions of the Operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PostgreSQL Operator 4.1 Minor Versions</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade41/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading Postgres Operator from 4.1.0 to a patch release This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade Postgres Operator 4.1 patch releases.
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! Prerequisites You will need the following items to complete the upgrade:
 The latest 4.1.X code for the Postgres Operator available The latest 4.1.X PGO client binary Finally, these instructions assume you are executing from $COROOT in a terminal window and that you are using the same user from your previous installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to PGO 3.5 From Previous Versions</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgradeto35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgradeto35/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading to Version 3.5.0 From Previous Versions This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade to Postgres Operator 3.5
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! For clusters created in prior versions that used pgbackrest, you will be required to first create a pgbasebackup for those clusters.
After upgrading to Operator 3.5, you will need to restore those clusters from the pgbasebackup into a new cluster with --pgbackrest enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>