<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upgrade on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upgrade on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 3.5 Minor Versions</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading Postgres Operator 3.5 Minor Versions This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade Postgres Operator 3.5 minor releases.
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! Prerequisites. You will need the following items to complete the upgrade:
 The latest 3.5.X code for the Postgres Operator available The latest 3.5.X PGO client binary Finally, these instructions assume you are executing from $COROOT in a terminal window and that you are using the same user from your previous installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 3.5 to 4</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35to4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade35to4/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading a Cluster from Version 3.5.x to PGO 4 This section will outline the procedure to upgrade a given cluster created using Postgres Operator 3.5.x to PGO version 4.1.
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! Prerequisites. You will need the following items to complete the upgrade:
 The latest PGO 4.1 code for the Postgres Operator available The latest PGO 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade PGO 4.0.1 to 4.1.0</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade40to41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgrade40to41/</guid>
      <description>Postgres Operator Upgrade Procedure from 4.0.1 to 4.1.0 This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade to Postgres Operator 4.1.0.
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! Prerequisites. You will need the following items to complete the upgrade:
 The latest 4.1.0 code for the Postgres Operator available The latest 4.1.0 PGO client binary Ensure you have a copy of the current pgouser and pgorole files for your environment and ensure you do not overwrite the current files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to PGO 3.5 From Previous Versions</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgradeto35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/upgrade/upgradeto35/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading to Version 3.5.0 From Previous Versions This procedure will give instructions on how to upgrade to Postgres Operator 3.5
As with any upgrade, please ensure you have taken recent backups of all relevant data! For clusters created in prior versions that used pgbackrest, you will be required to first create a pgbasebackup for those clusters.
After upgrading to Operator 3.5, you will need to restore those clusters from the pgbasebackup into a new cluster with --pgbackrest enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>