<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Environment</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/common-env/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/common-env/</guid>
      <description>For various scripts used by the Operator, the expenv utility is required as are certain environment variables.
Download the expenv utility from its Github Releases page, and place it into your PATH (e.g. $HOME/odev/bin).
The following environment variables are heavily used in the Bash installation procedures and may be used in Operator helper scripts.
   Variable Ansible Inventory Example Description     DISABLE_EVENTING pgo_disable_eventing false Disable Operator eventing subsystem   DISABLE_TLS pgo_disable_tls false Disable TLS for Operator   GOPATH  $HOME/odev Golang project directory   GOBIN  $GOPATH/bin Golang binary target directory   NAMESPACE namespace pgouser1 Namespaces monitored by Operator   PGOROOT  $GOPATH/src/github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Operator Using Bash</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/operator-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/operator-install/</guid>
      <description>A full installation of the Operator includes the following steps:
 create a project structure configure your environment variables configure Operator templates create security resources deploy the operator install pgo CLI (end user command tool)  Operator end-users are only required to install the pgo CLI client on their host and can skip the server-side installation steps. pgo CLI clients are provided for Linux, Mac, and Windows clients.
The Operator can be deployed by multiple methods including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Setup</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/developer-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/installation/developer-setup/</guid>
      <description>The Postgres-Operator is an open source project hosted on GitHub.
This guide is intended for those wanting to build the Operator from source or contribute via pull requests.
Prerequisites The target development host for these instructions is a CentOS 7 or RHEL 7 host. Others operating systems are possible, however we do not support building or running the Operator on others at this time.
Environment Variables The following environment variables are expected by the steps in this guide:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>