<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Using the pgo Client on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Using the pgo Client on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/pgo-cli-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/pgo-cli-overview/</guid>
      <description>PGO Command Line Interface (PGO CLI) One of the suppport methods of interacting with the PostgreSQL Operator is through the command line tool, pgo CLI.
The PGO CLI is downloaded from the GitHub Releases page for the PostgreSQL Operator (https://github.com/crunchydata/postgres-operator/releases).
The pgo client is provided in Mac, Windows, and Linux binary formats, download the appropriate client to your local laptop or workstation to work with a remote Operator.
PGO CLI Syntax Use the following syntax to run pgo commands from your terminal window:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Operations</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/common-pgo-cli-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/latest/operatorcli/common-pgo-cli-operations/</guid>
      <description>Common Operations In all the examples below, the user is specifying the pgouser1 namespace as the target of the operator. Replace this value with your own namespace value. You can specify a default namespace to be used by setting the PGO_NAMESPACE environment variable on the pgo client environment.
Cluster Operations A user will typically start using the Operator by creating a Postgres cluster as follows:
pgo create cluster mycluster -n pgouser1  This command creates a Postgres cluster in the pgouser1 namespace that has a single Postgres primary container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>